Mark Anthony Rathbone

Contact Details

PHONE NUMBER

+447984 682775

EMAIL ADDRESS

MarkAnthonyRathbone@gmail.com

WEBSITES

LINKEDIN / GITHUB

MARKRATHBONE.UK



Summary

I am an AWS and Microsoft Certified Solutions Architect, and I have 8 years of experience with tech troubleshooting and problem solving. I have working experience using serverless, data analytics, databases, and designing cloud architecture, as well as a large range of knowledge from various Cloud certifications. I am currently working on improving my knowledge of AI and Machine Learning, for both personal interest and professional improvement.

My experiences have equipped me with a range of technical skills in both physical and cloud environments. By working in customer facing roles I have become proficient in problem-solving under pressure and communicating with a varied audience. In my next role I am looking to continue my progression into Cloud Operations, so I can continue to test my skills to their limit, and continue to learn and develop.

Key Skills

Communication

Time Management

Teamwork

Growth Mindset

Persistence

Personal Responsibility

Experience

TRANSACT TECHNOLOGY SOLUTIONS

CLOUD ENGINEER

April 2021 → Present

At TransACT I work on the processes and pipelines behind FinOps. Creating, maintaining and re-architecting the current pipeline for better scalability in the future. Completed

company projects from end-to-end, from initial concepts to full rollout, for both internal employee use and for customer usage as added value to current product offerings. In addition I have helped transACT achieve Service Delivery Program validations.

During my time with transACT I have used a range of technology and services including Athena, Cloud Formation, Data Pipelines, EC2, EMR, Glue, Lambda (Python), Quicksight, Redshift, Step Functions and more.

JUNIOR CLOUD ENGINEER

February 2021 → April 2021

During my first two months at transACT I gained valuable perspective and experience with business to business relationships in technology, as well as experience with WARs, FinOps, and Cloud Architecture.

GENERATION UK AND IRELAND

AWS RE/START GRADUATE

June 2020 → September 2020

This 12 week full time programme covered classroom-based skills development and training on IT fundamentals. During the course I covered Linux, Python and Shell, in addition to AWS. This included learning about and becoming familiar with the monitoring and support of AWS and how to apply these services in the area of compute, storage and networking, including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lamda, Cloud Formation, RDS and Route 53.

Finally, during this programme I also developed my professional skills, resulting in improvements to my verbal and written communication. I also gained experience of explaining technical information and terminology to non technical end users.

RETAIL STAFF, FAST CAR DIRECT

October 2017 → **May 2018**

CUSTOMER SUPPORT ASSISTANT, MULTIMEDIA INTERNET CAFÉ

August 2009 → October 2017

Education & Certifications

CERTIFICATIONS (CREDLY)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate

2021

AWS Certified Data Analytics Speciality

AWS Certified Machine Learning Speciality

Microsoft Certified: Al Fundamentals

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

2020

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

HEATH PARK BUSINESS & ENTERPRISE COLLEGE

2007 - 2009